simpleveganblog.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - Simple Vegan Blog

_Effective data: June 4th, 2018_

WHO WE ARE

Simple Vegan Blog is run by Iosune y Alberto.

WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT AND WHY WE COLLECT IT

 **Email Address**

When you sign up for our mailing list, your email is kept by our mailing list provider, Mailchimp, for the purpose of sending newsletters via email.

 **Analytics**

We use Google Analytics to track anonymous usage data. Information is collected through the use of cookies and is used only to analyze site performance, and this gives us information on page views and site traffic (but NOT anything about who you are or any kind of personal information of any kind).

 **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

 **Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

Cookies are used by various plugins on our site in order to give me information about website visitors (analytics), to keep track of cookie consent/denial, and to monitor shop information.

You can also clear your browser cache of all data (many cookies only last for a “session,” i.e. the duration of your visit).

See our Cookie Policy and a list of all cookies currently used by our site here:

<https://simpleveganblog.com/cookie-policy>

You may opt out of cookies when you visit via the banner at the bottom of the page, and you may see how to cancel your consent from cookies on my Cookie Policy page (linked in the line above).

WHO WE SHARE YOUR DATA WITH

 **Mailchimp**

If you sign up for our mailling list, Mailchimp will have your name and email address.

 **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics only retains info about visitors, pages viewed, etc. GA does not collect any info that could identify you personally (but they collect data around the web in various forms and aggregate it).

 **Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Data collected by social media companies, such as that from embedded Youtube videos, becomes part of the data that Google collects.

 **Gravatar**

If you use Gravatar, when leaving a comment, an anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here:  
<https://automattic.com/privacy>

After approval of your comment, Gravatar uses that information to show your profile picture to the public in the context of your comment.

 **Akismet**

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

 **VaultPress**

We share the information related to to the comments you submit to the site with VaultPress, so they can back up all the data and we are able to restore it when needed.

HOW LONG WE RETAIN YOUR DATA

 **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics keeps data on site traffic indefinitely. While my site does not give Google any personal info about you, other websites might have at some point. You can find out more & use tools to manage your Google data here: <https://privacy.google.com/your-data.html>.

WHAT RIGHTS YOU HAVE OVER YOUR DATA

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

You can also request that we erase your data from our email list.

WHERE WE SEND YOUR DATA

 **Mailchimp**

MailChimp participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all Personal Information received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to each Framework’s applicable Principles.

 **Akismet, Gravatar and VaultPress**

Akismet, Gravatar and VaultPress are owned by Automattic, who take appropriate measures to ensure personal information is protected adequately in accordance with their Privacy Policy as required by applicable law.

For more information, visit: <https://automattic.com/privacy>

**WP Engine**

WP Engine comply with the EU – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland including the onward transfer liability provisions.

For more information, visit: <https://wpengine.com/legal/privacy>

HOW WE PROTECT YOUR DATA

Data protection is important for us. We use security measures such as two factor authentication, HTTPS encryption and other methods used by us ourselves and our hosting provider.

WHAT DATA BREACH PROCEDURES WE HAVE IN PLACE

If our mailing list is ever compromised, we will notify every subscriber and let them know what data was breached, to the best of our knowledge.

WHAT THIRD PARTIES WE RECEIVE DATA FROM

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. Our Site receive some data from them.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Site, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones.

By using our Site or services after the “Effective Date”, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy.

SALE OF BUSINESS OR ASSETS

In the event that the Site or substantially all of its assets is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, the information we have collected about you may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction.

CHILDREN UNDER 13

We care about protecting the privacy of children. We won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide us any personally identifying information. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as their names, email addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. If you’re under 13, please do not provide us with any personally identifying information (such as your name, your email address or your phone number).

CONTACT

If you have any questions or suggestions about our privacy policy, you can contact us via the contact page.  
<https://simpleveganblog.com/contact>
